

PROFILE

I am currently studying Software Engineering with Digital Technology (PwC) at Queens University Belfast.

I enjoy educating people on the impact of technology and how to use certain technologies as demonstrated within my role assisting in junior IT classes.

I am also an active member in the Queen's University Computing Society by attending talks hosted by the society and by participating within the 2020 Hack the COVID Hackathon. Within this event I, along with a team, presented our solution to a coronavirus specific problem to a panel of judges. I also participated in the 2021 Pediatrics Hackathon, in which I developed a mock app to assist in the flow of information from a responding paramedic to a specialist.

CONTACT

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/adamlogan42

Personal Website

https://adam-logan-portfolio.netlify.app/

(III) GitHub

https://aithub.com/adamlogan17

⊠ Email

adamlogan42@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems

- Windows 10
- Linux

Development Languages

- Python
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- **JavaScript**
- C++

Applications

- Microsoft Office
- G suite
- Azure
- Vantiq

ADAM OGAN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EDUCATION

Software Engineering with Digital Technology Partnership **Queens University Belfast**

2020 - 2024Level 1 Level 2 Architecture and 83 Professional & Transfer 86 Networks Skills Data Structures and Databases 85 82 **Algorithms** Fundamentals of Maths Software Engineering and 84 for Computing 91 Systems Development Software Design 88 Cyber Security 84 **Principles** Service Oriented 93 Web Technologies 77 Programming **Programming** 88



Belfast A-Levels School Belfast High School

2018 - 2020

Computer Science (A*); Mathematics (A); Chemistry (A)



Belfast High School

2016 - 2018

10 GCSEs A*-A including English and Maths

PROJECTS



Web Technologies Project

Within this project my team was tasked to create a web-based pointand-click escape room game. This demonstrates my creativity through creating a theme, story, and puzzles for this game. This project also shows my knowledge of web technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.



Belfast A-Level Project
High School Upper Sixth (Year 14)

For my A-level project I created a hotel booking system in Python with a GUI. During this project I produced documents detailing the stages of development such as research & analysis, design, and testing. I used several well-known Python libraries such as matplotlib, tkinter and sqlite3.

SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills

As can be seen above within my university projects and my work experience, I have been a part of many team projects which has assisted me in developing my communications skills and my ability to work effectively in a team.

Time Management

This skill is highlighted through my work experience as it demonstrates I can keep to deadlines given to me, by being organised. This skill is also proven by the fact that I managed to have a part-time job while attending school full-time.

Willingness to Learn

Within my spare time I read up on new concepts and technologies which I do not cover in university such as machine learning and the Linux command line. I also delve deeper into the technologies in which I study in university such as looking into the security issues of web technologies and exploring the NumPy and Pandas libraries in python.

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Running

This hobby of mine demonstrates that I am determined as I do not give up when tired. but I push on until the end of a task.

Reading

I enjoy reading as it allows me to broaden my horizons and expand my knowledge within the tech industry.

Programming

My interest in programming is one of the reasons why I decided to pursue a career in software development. The main aspect of programming which I enjoy is the many ways a problem can be solved.

AWARDS AND QUALIFICATIONS

Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Award PwC Digital Acumen Badge

Alteryx Designer Core

Understanding Business, Language and Tourism (Level 2)

Civica Award (Achieved by obtaining the highest mark in my Level 2 Software Engineering and Systems Development module)

WORK EXPERIENCE

PwC, Tech Consultant

14/06/2021-20/08/2021

As part of my apprenticeship program, I completed a 10-week placement with PwC over summer. Within the first half of this placement, I was trained on several technologies such as Azure, Alteryx, UiPath and excel.

The second half of my placement I was placed within the configuration team of a project which consisted of creating an online loan application process. Within this project I worked with salesforce, and more specifically salesforce flows, to make changes to the application process, which the client requested. I also manage the commercials and onboarding for a large project team (50+ colleagues), spanning two continents (PwC UK, CTech Poland and PwC South Africa) which demonstrates that my ability to work within a multicultural team.



Eason, Sales Assistant

19/02/2020 - 24/08/2020

My job at Eason's was heavily communication based. Everyday my role as a sales assistant required me to be polite and present myself in a friendly yet professional manner to the customers and my co-workers. This allowed me to develop my confident demeanour. Alongside this, working on the tills required cash handling which granted me the opportunity to prove I am trustworthy and thorough in all tasks I am asked to undertake.



PSNI, Software Engineer

29/07/2019 - 23/08/2019

At my 4 weeks' work experience with the PSNI, where I was placed within ICS in which I worked on several projects which were developing a facial recognition software, researching different handwriting recognition software and assisting ICS in finding a cloud storage provider. These projects tested both my problem-solving skills and my logical thinking skills.



PwC, Software Engineering

22/07/2019-26-07-2019

This week at PwC taught me how and the importance of sticking to deadlines and how to manage my time effectively to achieve this goal. I also got an insight on the day-to-day operations of large organisations and the structure in which these organisations may be built upon.



Catalyst, Product Designer

17/06/2019 - 20/06/2019

When I was at the Generation Innovation work experience program, I was placed within a team, and then my team was assigned to LibertyIT. My team and I then had to pitch our solution to a problem given to us by LibertyIT, to several members of the company. After this we had to deliver the same pitch to the other teams on the program. This work experience program helped me to become a more confident speaker.



Ulster University, Researcher

17/06/2019 - 20/06/2019

I spent three days at Ulster University, as part of the Sentinus Insight Into IT program, and this is where I conducted several experiments on virtual laboratories. This work experience program helped me to improve my report writing skills and my research skills through researching the different experiments which I carried out, such as an experiment on Brownian motion, and writing a report on these findings.